

Abdul Wahab

Web Developer

Done Masters in Web Engineering and Bachelors in Software Engineering, Learning day by day new technologies. Finding a career path in Software Development. Innovative and deadline-driven web developer with 3+ years of experience designing and developing websites and software from initial concept to final, polished deliverable.

≥ abwahab1995@gmail.com

Chemnitz, Germany

in linkedin.com/in/abdul-wahab

+49 1573 4931451

abproxer.github.io/profile/

ab_proxer@outlook.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer twentyZen GmbH

01/2021 - Present Dresden, Germany Tasks

- Custom PHP, Laravel, Javascript

- Applications Integration (NodeRed)

Data Warehousing and Visualization in PowerBI

Tools: VS Code, Confluence, Jira, MS-SQL, PowerBI

Work Student

inovisio communications GmbH &

05/2020 - 08/2020 Chemnitz, Germany

Tasks

- web application Testing (Selenium)

- PHP (Laminas Framework)

- mysql

Tools: VS Code, Selenium, mysql, Conflunce, wiki docs

IT Internee

Parker Hannifin Manufacturing Germany GmbH ☑

10/2019 - 04/2020 Chemnitz, Germany

Tasks

- mySQL

- Data Cleaning and ETL

- power BI Reporting Server and power BI Desktop,

- Microsoft SQL, SSIS

Tools: PowerBI, MS Report Builder, SSIS, MySQL

TECHNICAL SKILLS



PROJECTS

Visualization and Warehousing of Scientific Research Data

Master Thesis

Data Scraping for Restaurants Website

 Project to create a website where all scraped and cleaned data show through REST API in the fornend.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Head of IT skills in University

Served as a Head of IT skills in University society of Engineers.

Third position in Open House 2016

Third position in Open House 2016 held in National University of Modern Lanauaaes

LANGUAGES

English German Professional Working Proficiency Elementary Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

EDUCATION

Bachelors in SOFTWARE ENGINEERING National University of Modern Languages

06/2012 - 09/2016 Islamabad, Pakistan Courses

11/2017 - 08/2020

- Database Management - Software Engineering Systems Practice

Masters in Web Engineering

Technische Universität Chemnitz

Chemnitz, Germany

INTERESTS

Computer Gaming **IT News** Cricket GYM Communication Travelling